# LORI J. STRAVERS, MPH, CHES, CCRC

#### **EDUCATION**

West Virginia University, Morgantown, WV - Masters of Public Health Degree: 2005 Slippery Rock University of Pennsylvania, Slippery Rock, PA - BS, Community Health: 2001

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**CPR/BLS:** American Heart Association 2017-Present

**Certified Clinical Research Coordinator** (CCRC): Association of Clinical Research Professionals (ACRP) 2017-Present

Certified Health Education Specialist (CHES): National Commission for Health Education

Credentialing (NCHEC) 2001 - Present

Certified Yogafit Yoga Instructor: 2006 - Present

**PUBLICATIONS: Google Scholar** 

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a Certified Clinical Research Coordinator I excel at managing competing priorities in a professional and independent manner while adhering to complex study protocols and high data quality standards. As a Certified Health Education Specialist, I effectively assess, plan, and implement both individual and community health education and wellness interventions. I communicate effectively and possess excellent problem-solving, organizational, and interpersonal skills.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Quality Assurance and Compliance Associate - Duke University; Durham, NC: 2018-2018

- Assist in the development of a Clinical Quality Management Process, policies, and QA review tools for non-externally monitored studies in the School of Medicine
- Assist in the creation of staff QM training and analytics
- Assist in the creation of QM review tools to identify non-compliance risk areas and translate results into leadership reports
- Assist in the creation of a monitoring system to ensure ICH/GCP compliance

# **Clinical Research Coordinator -** Unified Women's Clinical Research; Raleigh, NC: 2017-2017

- Implemented and managed multiple industry-sponsored clinical trials
- Ensured compliance with ICH/GCP guidelines and ALCOA documentation standards
- Recruited and enrolled subjects per PI and central campaign referrals including cold calls
- Performed phlebotomy, vital sign measurements, and specimen collection and processing

**Social/Clinical Research Specialist** (Radiation Oncology and School of Public Health) - University of North Carolina Cancer Hospital; Chapel Hill, NC: 2008 – 2017

- Implemented multiple federal, industry, and investigator-initiated clinical trials including oversight of affiliate sites and subject databases (RedCap, MS Access, OnCore)
- Managed Institutional Review Board protocol submissions (new and renewals)
- Liaised with the Office of Sponsored Research to facilitate contract negotiations, budget proposals, and award approvals

- Monitored proposal statuses, COI documentation, and compliance timelines
- Prepared documentation for site monitoring visits and sponsor invoices for study procedures
- Quality Improvement / Lean Six Sigma Initiatives: created Symptom Management Clinic database; developed monthly Quality/Safety presentations highlighting departmental improvements; disseminated weekly Quality/Safety Committee meeting agendas and minutes; designed and updated department Good Catch recognition displays
- Assisted with reports, posters, interdepartmental and national conference presentations
- Assimilated literature reviews and submitted manuscripts to professional publications
- Redesigned department website for accuracy and easier navigation
- Supervised medical and work-study students
- Served as primary liaison between the interdisciplinary research team and study organizations (NC universities and community colleges)
- Collected quantitative and qualitative data for analysis and reporting
- Conducted key stakeholder interviews, environmental scans, and focus groups
- Supervised multiple data collection field teams
- Collaborated with research team to develop assessment and data collection tools for study
  protocols; recruit and minimize attrition of study participants; produce executive reports for
  study affiliates; Provide training workshops for assessment/data collection teams; host
  quarterly key stakeholder meetings; author journal articles for publications or presentations;
  interview and train new team members

# **Health Educator** – RediClinic; Midlothian, VA: 2007 – 2008

Consulted patients on healthy lifestyle, heart disease, and diabetes risk factors including follow-up phone calls on health status and normal laboratory results. Performed phlebotomy, glucose, cholesterol, and vital signs procedures as well as clinic management and administrative operations.

#### Wellness Coordinator – Longwood University; Farmville, VA: 2005 – 2007

- Directed campus wellness programming activities (Yogafit class, CommonHealth programs)
- Created wellness academic classes/activities and a citizenship training seminar (VA Girls State
- Instructed alcohol education classes for students sanctioned with alcohol violations
- Managed the Virginia state *Tobacco Use Control Project* grant
- Developed and maintained the Student Health website
- Chaired/co-chaired Sexual Assault Response Education and Wellness and Alcohol, Tobacco, and Other Drugs committees
- Supervised peer education, diversity groups, student internships and graduate assistants

## Wellness Program Coordinator West Virginia University; Morgantown, WV: 2001 – 2005

- Conducted annual worksite wellness employee health fairs and screenings
- Created Wellness program print and electronic marketing materials including website
- Developed individual nutrition assessments and aerobic/strength training programs
- Oriented new members to the Wellness Facility and supervised graduate student employees
- Performed body composition testing (Futrex 5000/XL Body Composition Analyzer)